<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Hammed Adigun</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Hammed Adigun</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unit Testing REST Services in Go</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/golang_automated_testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/golang_automated_testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Building software is a complex process. A software project perceived to be simple when started can easily grow to having thousands of lines of code. Also, unforeseen circumstances are common occurrence for any software project and this can cause a lot of unplanned changes. Making changes to a software can be very hard and unpredictable, especially when it is not done carefully, there has been many real life instances where numerous problems or bugs were introduce to a software due to some changes made to it. This is also known as regression bug - a bug introduced as a result of a change or changes in a system.&#xA;Writing automated tests is a great solution to minimising regression bug. Alongside with preventing regression bug, here are some other benefits of automated testing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up GitAction private repository access for Golang applications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/github_private_repo_access/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/github_private_repo_access/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, i&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a Go project that has dependencies on internal/private packages built in-house by the team, mostly to cut boilerplate or automate recurring processes. We&amp;rsquo;re using &lt;code&gt;go.mod&lt;/code&gt; to manage this project&amp;rsquo;s dependencies. One problem i &amp;amp; other member of the team often encounter is the GitAction error whenever we tried to access private repository/package from inside the project, most especially in &lt;code&gt;Dockerfile(s)&lt;/code&gt; or some simple &lt;code&gt;ci&lt;/code&gt; checks.&#xA;The solution to this problem is quite simple, even though it skipped my memory almost anytime i had to do it. This write-up is a small documentation for myself(easy future reference when i forget again :) )  and anyone out there facing similar issue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Golang Application on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/go-app-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/go-app-k8s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is a complete walk-through of how to deploy a monolithic Go web application in a Kubernetes cluster, how to attach a domain name so that it can be publicly accessible and finally, how to secure it with &lt;code&gt;LetsEncrypt&#39;s https and cert-manager&lt;/code&gt;. Lets ride!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;more-about-kubernetes&#34;&gt;&#xA;  More About Kubernetes&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#more-about-kubernetes&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes is a portable, extensible, open-source platform for managing containerized workloads and services, that facilitates both declarative configuration and automation. It has a large, rapidly growing ecosystem. Kubernetes services, support, and tools are widely available. Containers are a good way to bundle and run your applications. In a production environment, you need to manage the containers that run the applications and ensure that there is no downtime. For example, if a container goes down, another container needs to start. Wouldn’t it be easier if this behavior was handled by a system?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating Docker Registry Token Authentication Server with Go</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a_create_docker_auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a_create_docker_auth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was working on a project that uses a private docker registry to store docker images produced by users. The access to these images needs to be controlled so that user &lt;code&gt;foo&lt;/code&gt; MUST not be able to access(pull/push) images that belongs to user &lt;code&gt;bar&lt;/code&gt; . Also, a user should be able to authenticate with the private docker registry from their local or remote development machine with the famous docker login command, additionally users should be able to perform basic docker operations — docker push, pull etc with proper authentication and authorization. This is similar to Google cloud’s grc.io container registry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Docker Images Dynamically with Go</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/b_create_dynamic_image/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/b_create_dynamic_image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently started looking into ways of automating microservices app deployment and one of the many things i needed to automate is the famous docker build command. I understand that i could take advantage of the installed Docker client on the host computer by using os/exec package, but my idea isn’t that simple and its not really fun compared to using github.com/docker/docker/client — refer to as goDockerClient henceforth. This post contains the steps i followed to building docker images successfully with goDockerClient&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build and Deploy a secure REST API with Go, Postgresql, JWT and GORM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/c_build_api_with_go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/c_build_api_with_go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we are going to learn how to develop and deploy a secure REST api using Go Programming language.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;why-go&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Why Go?&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#why-go&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go is a very interesting programming language, it is a strongly typed language which compiles very fast, it performance is likened to that of C++, go has goroutines — a much more efficient replacement for Threads, and also go give you the freedom to static type on the web — I understand this is not new, i just love Go’s way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to resize images for better upload/download performance. Android Development.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/img_rzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/img_rzer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its not very common to see a project that doesn’t require photo upload in one form or the other. Most high end android device today create a photo as big as 2MB. This is a problem, How? Imagine you are building a mobile app that require your users to have a profile picture, having scalabilty in mind, each photo must not be &amp;gt; 100KB, am i right?. You dont want to save a 1MB photo for each user. It will not only affect your UX, your server would suffer as well. Uploading large photo to remote server can cause one or all of the following problems&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
